<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts from Anala</title>
    <link>/u_blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thoughts from Anala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/u_blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On blogging with R</title>
      <link>/u_blog/on-blogging-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/u_blog/on-blogging-with-r/</guid>
      <description>As noted previously, I use R for school and work when doing statistical computing using biomedical data. I tend to prefer sharing nicely formatted HTMLs generated from analyses conducted in R using R Markdown. Therefore, I was excited to learn that it was now possible to integrate “knitted” HTML output from an R Markdown (.Rmd) file to my Hugo blog with the assistance of the new R package, blogdown.
Quick start blogdown states that the “main [blog platform] we support in blogdown is Hugo”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On my favourite R packages</title>
      <link>/u_blog/on-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/u_blog/on-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>R is the statistical programming language I have used for a number of years in school and work as a Quantitative Biomedical Scientist. One reason I have enjoyed using R (particularly over SAS, but comparably to Python) is the large number of packages available for download to enhance the scope of analyses.
There are a set of packages I always load when starting an analysis:
 Everything in the tidyverse: the tidyverse includes packages that simplify data manipulation, data cleaning, data summarisation, and graphical representation of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/u_blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/u_blog/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Anala Gossai and I am a Quantitative Biomedical Scientist by education and practice. I specialize in deriving and communicating actionable insights from real-world health data using rigorous statistical methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On starting a blog</title>
      <link>/u_blog/on-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/u_blog/on-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Having a blog as a way to learn new technical skills and build my personal brand was something I wanted to attempt. Therefore, I spent a weekend building this static website that could host simple markdown documents or HTML outputs.
Although I have some familiarity with using Jekyll as a static site generator with GitHub Pages, I preferred the default aesthetics of Hugo with the Casper theme.
I started following the Quick Start guide for building and deploying Hugo as a GitHub Pages website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/u_blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/u_blog/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please e-mail me at anala.gossai@gmail.com.
I am also present on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>